SOMEBODY SAY THERE IS ALWAYS a way out
>> and is the wisdom OF GOD. BUSINESSMEN
HEAR ME. THERE IS ALWAYS A WAY OUT. I
REJOICE NOT OVER ME MY ENEMY. THE WISDOM
OF GOD IS AVAILABLE TO BAIL ME OUT. THE
WISDOM OF GOD IS AVAILABLE. EVEN
SALVATION WAS A DISPLAY of the wisdom OF
GOD THAT FROM THE FOUNDATIONS OF THE
EARTH THE LAMB WAS SLAIN.
THE WONDERS OF GOD.
HALLELUJAH.
ONE OF THE GREATEST DISPLAYS OF THE
WISDOM OF GOD WAS USING THE FOOLISHNESS
of death to redeem man. THE BIBLE SAYS
IF THEY HAD KNOWN THIS is called the
hidden wisdom OF GOD.
THAT WHEN SATAN WAS ALL ABOUT TRYING TO
INSTIGATE MEN to crucify JESUS AND JESUS
LOOKED LIKE HE was weak, it was wisdom
BEING DISPLAYED. RESPECT THOSE WHO ARE
STRONG BUT ACT WEAK. THERE IS PROFOUND
WISDOM WHEN THE STRONG LOOK LIKE THEY
are weak.
BEFORE PONTIOUS PILATE, PONTIOUS PILOT
SAID, "DON'T YOU KNOW THAT I HAVE THE
POWER TO REDEEM YOU?" MY GOODNESS. AND
THE ALL WISE GOD WAS WATCHING WHEN HE
HUNG UPON THE CROSS. I CAN IMAGINE THE
JOY IN SATAN'S HEART. FINALLY, WE GOT
HIM. YOU REFUSE TO BOW AND HE SAID INTO
YOUR HANDS I COMMIT MY SPIRIT AND AS
soon as he gave UP THE GHOST I CAN
IMAGINE HELL DANCING SUDDENLY A STRANGER
ENTERS THE HELL THE Bible says when he
got there he spoiled principalities and
powers I CAN MARRY SATAN SAID WHAT IS
THIS YOU ARE DEAD NOW WATCH THIS
DEATH FOR HIM WAS NOT PUNISHMENT IT WAS
THE CHANNEL TO go to Hades and to
collect the keys.
It's in your Bible. The Bible says
according to Peter's epistle, he opened
the gates THAT THE DEPARTED SAINTS, HE
SAID, "YOU ARE FREE. COME, LET'S GO."
AND THE BIBLE SAYS HE RESURRECTED AS THE
FIRSTBORN OF THE BEGOTTEN. AND THEY ALSO
RESURRECTED AND WALKED ROUND THE STREETS
OF JERUSALEM.
Let me explain to you for one minute and
then we'll pray. what Jesus did.
Look at this.
It's like a man who always had a PhD but
he had it alone.
You get my illustration. Then he strips
himself of the PhD and becomes like an
illiterate
goes back to nursery, primary, secondary
school, university. Are we together? AT
THE POINT OF OBTAINING PHD AGAIN that he
always had. He now said hold on
and he did something profound. He
carried you along.
Are we together? And hid you in him and
the day they gave him PhD every other
person had PhD appear. AND WE STARTED
SAYING WHERE did this come from? And
they said but you earn PhD say me? No
PhD he always HAD BUT HE DID NOT WANT TO
have it alone. He also wanted you to
have it. So he left it. He came BACK
WENT THROUGH THAT JOURNEY AGAIN. THAT'S
WHAT HE DID WITH his life. He had
salvation. He had the life the authority
but he had it alone. Are we together
now? And the Bible says he stripped
himself and then he grafted you in him
by covenant. It was Apostle Paul who was
given that revelation. I have been
CRUCIFIED WITH CHRIST. NOT JUST THAT
JESUS DIED FOR ME. THE GOSPEL TEACHES
THAT JESUS DIED, BUT APOSTLE Paul said,
"I died too in him." And when HE ROSE
AGAIN, I ROSE AGAIN IN HIM. NOW THAT
HE'S SEATED, I AM SEATED with him. He
calls US PARTAKERS OF HIS DIVINE NATURE,
the wisdom of God.
and through the foolishness of the
gospel that if any man believes that
report as frail as he is I am not
ashamed of the gospel OF CHRIST HE SAYS
FOR IT IS THE POWER OF GOD LISTEN BY THE
MERCIES OF GOD AS I TRAVEL AROUND THE
nations preaching the GOSPEL I AM AMAZED
AT THE WISDOM of God that was hidden
through the foolishness OF THE GOSPEL
YOU CAN FIND A MAN IN SUCH DEPRAVITY BUT
YOU WILL HEAR THE GOSPEL AND UPON
DECLARING THE LORDSHIP OF JESUS A
MIRACLE HAPPENS TO THAT MAN THAT SAUL
CAN TURN TO PAUL THAT RAHAB CAN FIND
HOPE BECAUSE OF THE FOOLISHNESS OF THE
GOSPEL.
Can I tell you this? Only a fool will
say in his heart there is no God. You
know the reason. Romans 1 and verse 20.
Let's find somewhere and then we'll
begin to pray. Everybody please read.
It's a long read but I want you to read.
One to go. For the invisible things of
him from the creation of the world are
clearly seen, being understood by the
things that are made, even his eternal
power and godhead. Why?
>> You are not WITHOUT EXCUSE. YOU CAN'T
SAY THERE IS A GOD. WATCH THE FISH. They
will teach you that there is God. Watch
the plants. We mine oil. IS BECOME A AN
EXPENSIVE commodity today. We go down
the earth and mine oil.
Are we together? And they go through ALL
KINDS OF PROCESSES AND BECOME VARIOUS
THINGS THAT ARE A BLESSING to man today.
The God of heaven,
the only wise God.
Number one, it causes you to praise him.
But number two, it also creates a desire
in you to allow that dimension of his
wisdom to find expression in you because
as he is the Bible says so are we. That
means everyone who is born of God
genuinely. Someone learning now a
dimension of the wisdom of God must be
trapped and revealed in your life
eventually beyond age eventually BEYOND
ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION. THAT'S THE VALUE
OF THE HOLY SPIRIT. THAT'S WHY THERE IS
A DIMENSION of the Holy Spirit called
the spirit of wisdom that there is a
spirit in man who said and the breath of
the almighty can make any man ordinary
man to be of understanding.
Number three,
the third way we know God
and explore his wonders
is through the study of his power.
So number one, his wisdom, his
attributes or his nature. Number two,
his wisdom. Number three, his power.
Exodus chapter 15, please. We'll begin
our reading from verse one.
Exodus 15 and verse one. Then sang Moses
and the children of Israel this song
unto the Lord and spake, saying, I will
sing unto the Lord, for he has triumphed
gloriously. The horse and his rider have
he thrown into the sea. Verse two, the
Lord is my strength and song. He's
become my salvation. He is my God and I
will prepare him an habitation. My
father's God and I will exalt him. VERSE
THREE, PLEASE PAY ATTENTION. The Lord is
a man of war. The Lord is his name.
Pharaoh's chariots and his horse had he
cast into the sea. His chosen captains
also are drowned in the sea. Verse five,
the depths have covered them. They sank
into the bottom as a stone. Six, thy
right hand, oh God, is become what?
Glorious in power. Thy right hand, oh
God, had dashed in pieces the enemy.
Seven. And the greatness of thy
excellency, and the greatness of thy
excellency, thou hast overthrown them
that rose up against thee, thou sentest
forth thy wrath, and it consumed them as
trouble. Verse eight.
And with the blast of thy nostrils,
where the waters gathered together, the
flood stood upright as an hip, and the
depths were congealed in the heart of
the sea. Verse 9, it says, "The enemy
said, I will pursue. I will overtake. I
will divide the spoil and LOSS SHALL BE
SATISFIED. MY LOSS SHALL BE satisfied
upon them. I will draw my sword and my
hand shall destroy them. Verse 10. Thou
this blow with thy wind and the sea
COVERED THEM. THEY SANK AS lead in the
mighty waters. 11. Who is like unto
thee, O Lord, AMONG THE GODS? WHO IS
LIKE THEE? IT SAYS YOU ARE GLORIOUS in
holiness, fearful in praises, doing
verse 12, thou stretchest out thy hand,
and the earth swallowed them. The final
verse 13, thou in thy mercy has led
forth the people which thou HAST
REDEEMED, AND HAS GUIDED THEM IN THY
STRENGTH UNTO THY holy habitation. God
is powerful. HE'S NOT ONLY A good God.
He's not only THE ALL- WISE GOD, HE IS
ALL POWERFUL. CONSIDER THE FOLLOWING
SCRIPTURES, PLEASE. I'd like the
scriptures to speak for themselves and
we'll pray. Psalm 77 and verse14.
77 and verse14. Thou art the God that
DOETH WONDERS. IT SAYS, "THOU HAS
DECLARED thy strength among the people."
Do you LOVE SCRIPTURES? PSALM 105 and
verse 5. 105 and verse 5. Psalm 105 and
verse 5. Be patient as we look at this
scripture. It said, "Remember his
marvelous works which he has done, HIS
WONDERS AND THE JUDGMENTS OF his mouth."
Job 5 and verse 9. Job 5 and verse 9. It
says, "Which doeth great things and
unsearchable, MARVELOUS THINGS WITHOUT
NUMBER." PSALMS 40 AND VERSE 5. Psalms
40 and verse 5.
Many, oh Lord, my God, are thy wonderful
works which thou hast done, AND THY
THOUGHTS WHICH TO US WORD, they cannot
be reckoned up in order unto thee. If I
would declare or speak of them, it says
they are more than that which can be
numbered. Let me give you a final
scripture so that we rejoice at the
things that God can do. THE POWER OF GOD
CAUSING WONDROUS THINGS IN THE LIFE OF a
man. Luke chapter 18 I believe and verse
27 Jesus was speaking and he made a
profound statement. He said the things
which are impossible with men.
Huh?
The things which are impossible with
men.
So when the doctor says, "I've done my
best," thank them.
But know that there is always a way out.
That power of God can cause wondrous
things to be wrought in a man. This is
wonderful. I have seen miracles in my
life. Believe me, I have seen all kinds
of miracles. And you will think because
these miracles flow from God through
you, you will get used to it. For every
time I watch WITH WONDER, HOW DOES
SOMEBODY JUST GET UP FROM A WHEELCHAIR?
I MEAN, YOU WATCH THE PERSON COME, THE
LEGS ARE SO THIN, SOMETIMES YOU ARE EVEN
AFRAID IF THE PERSON STANDS LIKE IT WILL
BREAK AND YET THEY GET UP AND THEY'RE
JUMPING and running. A wonder walking
power. This one is not wisdom. This one
is power. There are things in your life
you don't need wisdom. YOU NEED POWER.
WHEN THE ENEMY ATTACKS YOU, YOU need
power. Psalm 66 and:e3, say unto God,
how terrible are THOU IN THY WORKS.
THROUGH THE GREATNESS OF THY POWER SHALL
THY ENEMIES SUBMIT THEMSELVES TO THEE.
OUR LORD GOD, THOU HAS MADE THE HEAVENS
AND THE EARTH BY THY GREAT POWER. Is
there anything that is too hard for you
to do? Please answer.
That means God can GIVE YOU A JOB THIS
WEEK. AH, that means you CAN HAVE A
CHILD BEFORE the years.
A God that doeth wonders.
I have seen the power of God at work.
Not just in healing bodies, but I've
seen him move mightily. And he will
allow men to conclude about you and say
you cannot rise. Then here he comes. He
says let me hold you by myself. Woe
bides a man who tries to fight you. When
it is God holding your hand. He's not
just the all- wise God. He's the all
powerful God. When he asks men to lift
you and they refuse, he will come by
himself and say, "Give me your hands."
And when God holds your hands, my
brothers and my sisters,
do you believe this?
One day
I I went to the redemption camp and um
many of you may have heard me say the
story and while I was passing pastor I
was looking at the labelings on the
shares and I saw
174,000
and this right know how you write share
two share three and I thought to myself
I said my goodness
that there is a chair that has a label
174,000
all converging AND THIS IS LIKE 10% or
maybe sometimes less.
WHAT KIND OF A GOD WOULD gravitate
people and plant an interest in their
hearts to converge IN ONE PLACE NOT
ONLINE? WHAT SORT OF A GOD IS THAT? IS
THERE ANY KIND OF academic intelligence
that can explain this? TALK TO ME
INTELLIGENCE PEOPLE. WHAT SORT OF
BUSINESS idea can gravitate people from
all walks of life? No sir. It is the
power of God at work in the world of
men.
Is someone learning now?
>> The wonder working power of God causing
praise.
I live a life of reverence unto God. Not
just because
um that is the way it should be as a
believer, but because as he increases my
knowledge of him, it compels me to get
down on my knees. There are times that
we finish a program and while
everybody's celebrating, I go back home
and I get down on my knees and I say,
"God, what is this?
What is this? What is this?" The wisdom
of God at work in a man. What is this?
the power of God at work in men. What is
this? Sometimes when I'M READING MY
BIBLE, DO you know honestly I just rest
my head and I say, "God, what is this?"
IT'S AS IF THESE THINGS DID NOT HAPPEN.
You read THE BIBLE THAT THERE WAS ONCE
UPON a time THE RED SEA PARTED. IT WAS
NOT A PARABLE. MEN ACTUALLY WALKED ON
DRY GROUND. THERE IS A DAY IT HAPPENED
THAT A DAY MANA CAME FROM HEAVEN ALREADY
PREPARED THAT THERE WAS ONCE UPON A TIME
THE PROPHET WENT TO BROOK CHERIT AND
THERE WAS A RAVEN THAT WILL BRING HIM
MEAL THAT ONCE UPON A TIME FIVE LOAVES
AND TWO FISH FED 5,000 PEOPLE ASSIGNED
women and children. Do you not believe
YOUR BIBLE AGAIN THAT A MAN DIED AND
CAME BACK TO LIFE WITHOUT ANYBODY
CALLING HIM BACK? EVERY OTHER PERSON WHO
DIED, SOMEONE ALIVE HAD TO CALL HIM
BACK. BUT HERE IS A MAN WHO DIED AND
THERE WAS NO MAN TO CALL HIM BACK. YET
HE RESURRECTED BY the power OF THE
SPIRIT.
YOUR BIBLE SAYS so
that on THE DAY OF PENTECOST
120 people after receiving the Holy
Ghost today there's about 2.6 BILLION
PEOPLE AND REGARDLESS OF PERSECUTION
THROUGH HISTORY THE GOSPEL STILL STANDS.
WHAT KIND OF POWER IS THAT?
THE POWER THAT CAN TURN A MAN WHO WAS A
murderer receiving letters from a high
PRIEST TO PERSECUTE THE CHURCH. HE WAS
THE ONE WHO WROTE ABOUT TWOTHIRDS OF THE
NEW TESTAMENT. WHAT KIND OF POWER IS
THAT? THAT A YOUNG MAN WAS SOLD BY HIS
BROTHERS AND HE WENT TO EGYPT NOT
KNOWING HE WAS ON THE PATH OF DESTINY
AND A FEW YEARS LATER ON HE WOULD BECOME
THE PRIME MINISTER LIFTED BY THE HAND OF
GOD. DO YOU NOT KNOW THAT IS THE POWER
OF GOD? THE POWER THAT TAKES YOU FROM
ANYWHERE TO ANYWHERE. Anywhere to
anywhere, anywhere to anywhere in the
name of Jesus. LET ME PROPHESY over you.
BY THAT SAME POWER THAT RAISED CHRIST
FROM THE DEAD, you rise from where you
are to the place of destiny. You rise
FROM WHERE YOU ARE TO THE PLACE OF
DESTINY. The power that lifts men will
lift you. The power that heals men will
heal you. The power that delivers will
deliver you in the name of Jesus.